SHEFALI. MAKRAND. SULE

E mail id- shefali.sule@gmail.com Phone - +919712941486

LinkedIn ID - www.linkedin.com/in/shefali-sule-13540b122

Current Address - 'Yeshwant-Dwarka' Row House no. 23, Shankar Maharaj Soc. Market-Yard, Pune 411037

Experience Summary:

A highly motivated professional with around 11 Years' experience in the complete cycle of Human Resource process.

Specialized in development of Human Resource Management with companies who are either planning or are in process of transformation or reformation of the company. The companies who are looking for a Team Handler who understands the company's development and employment management during progressing state.

Work Experience

1. Bluegrey Technologies India Pvt Ltd. - HR Manager

April 2021 - June 2024

- Enhances the organization's human resources by planning, implementing, evaluating employee relations, human resources policies, programs, and practices.
- Cultivates professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops, reviewing professional publications, establishing personal networks, and participating in professional societies
- Enforces management guidelines by preparing, updating, and recommending human resource policies and procedures.
- Ensures planning, monitoring, and appraisal of employee work results.
- Train managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Hearing and resolving employee grievances, and counseling employees and supervisors.
- Maintain proper records of employee punch in/punch outs, break timings, leave management, documentations, timely delivery of payslips and accurate salary calculations.
- Supports organization by recruiting the best workforce available in the budget.
- Supports organization by establishing a recruiting, testing, and interviewing program; counseling managers on candidate selection; conducting and analyzing exit interviews; and recommending changes.
- Closing working with hiring vendor partners and evaluating their performances on a timely basis.
- Retains historical human resource records by designing a filing and retrieval system and keeping
 past and current records.
- Manage ESIC & PF process as and when required.

- 2. Corigami Technologies HR and Admin Officer
- December 2019 April 2021
- Working as an HR and Admin head for the India Office.
- Handling the complete recruitment process for the company and also managing the staffing consultancies.
- Planning the hiring process as per the requirement.
- Conducting the campus recruitment.
- Conducting complete documentation and verification process.
- Making of agreements between vendors/permanent employees/contractual employees.
- Conducting quarterly performance review.
- Conducting the payroll process.
- Formation and upgradation of Company norms and policies.
- Market research for the skills and working patterns.
- Keeping upgradation of the government rules and regulations.
- Releasing the pending bills of the vendors and other affiliated members.
- Maintaining the complete details about the monthly company expenses.
- Managing the office equipment.
- 3. Rigel Networks Delivery Lead

September 2019 – December 2019

- Manage and drive full-cycle recruitment process including sourcing, screening, interview, feedback and offers for all levels of candidates from entry to senior level
- Building a pipeline of top local and passive talent through researching, sourcing and networking
- Hands-on experience in hiring for different Technical roles
- Effectively manage multiple priorities across the business including project orientation such as a strong focus on diversity and inclusion
- Proactive talent engagement: develop custom research, target lists and sourcing strategies for current and future positions
- 4. Self-Owned Business

Apr 2018 to August 2019

- Working for well-known restaurant chains and 4 stars / 5-star Hotel of country as vendor.
- 5. Arche Softronix Pvt. Ltd Team Lead

June 2016 to Feb 2018

- Coordination with the Client for new requirements and responsible for the work allocation to the team members.
- Gathering Market Information/data for effective and appropriate use at times. Interacting with all tech panels, Scheduling Interview, getting the feedback, follows up on their joining.
- Ensured and targeted daily and weekly resume counts were hit and ensured resumes were to company format and to client's expectations before sent out.
- Created weekly recruiting activity reports for management.
- Responsible for dealing with new clients.
- Getting Leads for Empanelment of New Clients/Customers.

- Actively doing recruitments for across IT project segments, Resource Augmentation and experience in Full Life Cycle of deployment of resources through Partners, Web portals (Monster, Naukri, and TimesJob etc), networking, Personal Contacts, advertisement - Fulfilling requirements across all the spectrum of skills.
- Co-ordinating with the account managers for new requirements and responsible for the work allocation to the team members.
- Gathering Market Information/data for effective and appropriate use at times. Interacting with all tech panels, Scheduling Interview, getting the feedback, follows up of their joining.
- Interacting with the employers for completing the papers work, like preparing the Task order, signing the master agreement.
- Handling issues on Master Agreement regarding the payment terms.
- Interacting with the Account department for any payment issues related to consultant.
- Follow up with the consultant to get the feedback on the project.
- Ensured and targeted daily and weekly resume counts were hit and ensured resumes were to company format and to client's expectations before sent out.
- Creating screening form (skill chart) for the candidates, preparing questions for the initial screening of candidates.
- Making cold calling, passive recruitment, initial and a quality screening of candidates, reference check
- Involved in doing job posting in various job portals.
 - Regular follow-up with the candidates and Account managers till the purchase order is achieved.
 - Interact with Senior Account Managers across different verticals in fulfilling their Requirements.
 - Database building and management
 - Short listing the Candidates and arranging interviews
 - Responsible for posting ads on different job boards on the Internet.
 - Reviewed all resumes, identified potential candidates, and prescreened them using a questionnaire
- 7. Avancos Management Service Pvt. Ltd.

June 2014 to December 2014 (6 months)

Position: Executive RecruiterRole: Pure recruiting in IT field

Internship

1. TCS Vadodara

Project assigned: "Analysis of the Recruiting process TCS"

- Diligently worked in the Recruiting department for around 2 months.
- Helped them with their current procedure.
- Found out the loops and with them found the solution too.

• Made a close relation with the employees also to find out what are their current opinions about the employees about the current work environment.

Education

SR. NO	DEGREE	UNIVERSITY/ INSTITUTE	Year
1.	MBA (HR)	ITM (GTU affiliated)	2014
2.	BBA (HR)	Navrachana University	2012
3.	HSC	GHSEB	2009
4.	SSC	GHSEB	2007

Personal Details

Birth date- 13th November 1991

Gender- Female

Marital Status - Married

Declaration

I hereby declare the above information to be the correct to my knowledge.

Place- Pune

Name- Shefali. M. Sule